<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: ruby | Beerlington]]></title>
  <link href="http://beerlington.github.io/blog/categories/ruby/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://beerlington.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-12-31T21:18:39-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://beerlington.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Peter Brown]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Reflection on Organizing the Burlington Ruby Conference]]></title>
    <link href="http://beerlington.github.io/blog/2013/08/15/a-reflection-on-organizing-the-burlington-ruby-conference/"/>
    <updated>2013-08-15T21:19:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://beerlington.github.io/blog/2013/08/15/a-reflection-on-organizing-the-burlington-ruby-conference</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/images/burlington-ruby-conference-banner-small.png" alt="Burlington Ruby Conference Banner" /></p>

<p>&ldquo;Why are you organizing a conference?&rdquo; &ndash; Someone asked me this question when we were just starting to plan for this year&rsquo;s Burlington Ruby Conference. I don&rsquo;t remember my exact response, but it was probably a long the lines of &ldquo;Uhhhh I don&rsquo;t know, it&rsquo;s just something I want to do&rdquo;. I remember thinking &ldquo;why wouldn&rsquo;t you want to do it?&rdquo;. I was really excited about it and it felt like one of those things I was supposed to do.</p>

<p>It turns out that doing it well takes a lot of hard work. I&rsquo;m estimating that I spent over 200 hours on this year&rsquo;s event, not including the nights I dreamt about it. I&rsquo;m not sure where that stands compared to other web developers who moonlight as conference organizers, but I&rsquo;m guessing it&rsquo;s on the higher end of the spectrum. I can&rsquo;t picture many developers devoting that much time to something software-related that isn&rsquo;t coding. For me though, the payoff has been huge. While I haven&rsquo;t benefited financially, I&rsquo;ve learned a lot about planning and budgeting, made some awesome friends, and had what I would consider one of the best experiences of my life.</p>

<p>It has been almost two weeks since the conference ended, so I wanted to jot down a few of my thoughts on it before they faded.</p>

<h2>Goals for this year</h2>

<p>This was the 2nd year for the Burlington Ruby Conference. I was not very involved last year, other than helping with a last minute scramble to try and find attendees. This year I wanted to be more involved. When we started planning back in January, we knew there were a few things that needed to change in order to make it an event we could continue to do. To understand what I mean, let&rsquo;s take a look at last year&rsquo;s conference by the numbers:</p>

<p>Last year:</p>

<ul>
<li>Attendees: 75</li>
<li>Speakers: 7</li>
<li>Women: &lt; 10%</li>
<li>Sponsors/supporters: 1</li>
<li>Budget: $12K</li>
</ul>


<p>A conference with only 75 attendees and almost no sponsors is simply not sustainable. Including sponsors, our budget for last year&rsquo;s event was just over $12K. We did not plan on having a conference this small, but as most first-year organizers know all too well, things rarely go as planned. We had to cut back on a lot of things at the last minute, such as the venue size, and it was stressful for everyone involved. In order to make the conference sustainable, we knew we needed to increase our budget and attendance. We set a few goals for this year that we knew were ambitious, but would allow us to run the conference without having to forgo the things we felt were essential.</p>

<p>Our Goals for this year:</p>

<ul>
<li>Attendees: 150</li>
<li>Speakers: 10</li>
<li>Increase female attendance + speakers</li>
<li>Sponsors: MOAR</li>
<li>Video recordings</li>
<li>Keep ticket prices low</li>
<li>Budget: $20K</li>
</ul>


<p>We knew that increasing our attendance and budget by 2x was an ambitious goal. How were we going to get 150 people to come to Vermont for a software conference? How were we going to raise enough money to double our budget and be able to afford some of the nice to haves such as video recordings? How could we increase diversity?</p>

<p>It took a lot of hard work and creativity to reach these goals, and here are a few of the things we did to achieve them.</p>

<h2>MOAR Speakers</h2>

<p>Last year&rsquo;s conference did not have an official call for proposals. All of the speakers were personally invited. When we started thinking about getting speakers at this year&rsquo;s conference, we were sort of naive and wanted to avoid a formal CFP and just do invite-only again. We compiled a list of people that we wanted to speak at the conference and began reaching out to them. We had a couple &lsquo;Yes&rsquo;s, but most of them either said they were busy or just didn&rsquo;t reply. We were a little discouraged, so I <a href="https://twitter.com/btvrubyconf/status/306520777455460352">tweeted at @devchix</a> asking for help getting the word out. 15 minutes later, <a href="https://twitter.com/ashedryden">Ashe Dryden</a> replied saying that she wanted to help us make the process more friendly to diverse groups. Ashe had written a blog post on <a href="http://ashedryden.com/blog/increasing-diversity-at-your-conference">how to increase diversity at your conference</a> that I would consider the bible on this subject. She encouraged us to publish a <a href="http://burlingtonruby.com/diversity.html">diversity statement</a> and <a href="http://burlingtonruby.com/conduct.html">code of conduct</a>, organize a blind speaker selection process, as well as helped us organize a few Google hangouts to meet potential speakers.</p>

<p>The Google hangouts proved to be invaluable for finding great speakers. Two of my favorite speakers this year both happened to be in those hangouts. They seemed very excited about the conference, and since they made it through the blind proposal selection and into the final round, we decided to pick both of them. We ended up with 52 submissions and increased the total number of speakers from 10 to 12, though it didn&rsquo;t make the selection process any easier. For those who submitted and were not selected, I spent a few hours sending personalized emails delivering the bad news. A few people replied asking how they could improve their proposals, but unfortunately with 52 submissions and only 9 slots, it was really not about quality. This was definitely one of the hardest parts of the entire experience for me.</p>

<h2>MOAR Sponsors</h2>

<p>&ldquo;Let&rsquo;s just get more sponsors&rdquo;. This was probably the most naive thought I had going into planning this year&rsquo;s conference. The thing about sponsors is that unless you have a direct connection or are an established event, it&rsquo;s pretty much impossible to find them. There are three reasons I can think of why someone would sponsor a conference. 1) They&rsquo;re hiring, 2) they&rsquo;re marketing a product, and/or 3) to support their community. As I mentioned in my <a href="/blog/2013/04/06/building-a-strong-foundation-for-vermonts-technology-future/">previous blog post</a>, we didn&rsquo;t have much traction from our local community in terms of financial support, but I thought it would be different if we reached out beyond our local community. Sadly this was not the case. If a company is selling a product or hiring, they want to know that their target audience will be in attendance. They need to know the conference is worth it for them. If they were basing their response on last year&rsquo;s conference, 75 attendees is not a lot of people to get in front of. After &ldquo;cold emailing&rdquo; a TON of companies and getting zero &lsquo;Yes&rsquo;s, it became apparent that we were wasting our time and would need to focus our attention on ticket sales. More on sponsorship in a bit&hellip;</p>

<h2>MOAR Attendees</h2>

<p>Going from 75 to 150 attendees is kind of a big deal. After making the decision to grow, I started to wonder, &ldquo;is this too many people for our second year?&rdquo;. How do you even reach that many people? There are now close to <a href="http://lanyrd.com/topics/ruby/">20 Ruby conferences</a> in the U.S each year, and that number is still increasing. While having a high number of these regional conferences is great for the community, it puts a lot of pressure on the organizers to provide a unique experience. Why would someone fly across the country for a conference when they have one in their own region or state, or even their own city?</p>

<p>We needed to give people a reason to want to come. One of the nice things about Vermont is that it&rsquo;s a beautiful state and people love to vacation here. We recognized that in order to bring people to the conference, we&rsquo;d need to focus on why <em>we</em> believed people should come. Our goal for Burlington Ruby is to build community and have fun. We see it as an excuse for people to come to Vermont for a weekend vacation, away from their normal, busy lives. Oh, and there just so happens to be a Ruby conference taking place.</p>

<p>I live in Vermont for its slower pace and quality of life. This laid back nature is evident in our schedule (long breaks) and the types of talks we had. We decided to focus our marketing on Vermont&rsquo;s beauty and not try and be something we weren&rsquo;t. We&rsquo;re a small conference focused on having a fun, relaxing weekend and making friends.</p>

<p>People seemed to take notice:</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p>There is a reason to visit Burlington, VT, besides Heady Topper. <a href="http://t.co/urpdJVWqX7">http://t.co/urpdJVWqX7</a></p>&mdash; Hiro Asari (@hiro_asari) <a href="https://twitter.com/hiro_asari/statuses/311518675708555264">March 12, 2013</a></blockquote>


<script async src="http://beerlington.github.io//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>


<h2>The history of the cat sponsors and Ruby toys</h2>

<p>We also wanted to put on a conference that matched our personalities and felt like it belonged here in Burlington.</p>

<p>The cat sponsors and Ruby catnip toys were never something we set out to do. Early in the planning, we decided we wanted to do some sort of workshop to try and get people excited about Ruby and want to come to the conference. I reached out to <a href="https://twitter.com/Mo_Mack">Maureen McElaney</a> who had just started a <a href="http://www.girldevelopit.com/chapters/burlington">Burlington chapter of Girl Develop It</a>. She was excited to meet with us and organize a workshop via GDI. During our initial conversation, the topic of sponsors came up, and Brett and I were discussing the lack of support we were getting from our local community. We started joking about how we were just going to have cats sponsor us, and two days later, <a href="http://burlingtonruby.com/cat.html">the first official conference cats</a> were born.</p>

<p>One month after the cats went live, and still no traction with sponsors, I was sitting there thinking about how great cats are, and decided we needed cat toys to go with the cat sponsors. I reached out to a local artist who had an <a href="http://www.etsy.com/shop/cattitudecattoy">Etsy store</a> and asked if she would be interested in making Ruby shaped catnip toys that we could sell at the conference. I felt like an idiot and thought she would think I was crazy, but she got back to me literally 5 minutes later and said she was interested in making them. She went ahead and made a trial run, and after a week we had the first official Ruby conference catnip toys.</p>

<p><img src="/images/ruby-catnip-cat-toys.jpg" alt="Burlington Ruby Conference catnip cat toys" /></p>

<p>We mailed out some of the toys to people who had helped us out so far, and figured it would be a good way to get the word out. Soon <a href="http://instagram.com/p/aj3FIsgASy/">pictures</a> and <a href="https://vine.co/v/bEe3MDpDvhQ">videos</a> started popping up on Twitter, and we were getting a lot more traffic to our website. We don&rsquo;t really have any way of knowing, but I&rsquo;m curious how many people came to the conference either directly or indirectly because of the cats.</p>

<h2>Dropping sponsorship prices</h2>

<p>We sold nearly half the total tickets during our initial early bird ticket sale (aka &ldquo;Fresh Tracks&rdquo;). Then things slowed down to a crawl. The good news was that we had already sold more tickets than we did the previous year. The bad news was that we still had 75 to go in order to reach our goal. We knew that if we sold enough tickets, we would at least be able to afford to put on the event and not lose a ton of money. Since we didn&rsquo;t have any traction with sponsors, we decided to drop the sponsorship prices to the point where we were basically selling the tickets in bulk. For slightly more than the individual cost of a ticket, you got to be a sponsor. Not a bad deal. This definitely worked in our favor as we started to have a few sponsors actually reaching out to us.</p>

<h2>Ruby Workshop</h2>

<p>We felt strongly that the Ruby workshop was important to have in conjunction with the conference. Burlington has a very small developer community, and last year we had very few Vermonters in attendance. As I mentioned ealier, we met with Maureen to plan out a Ruby training/workshop, and she took the idea and ran with it. The workshop happened one week before the conference and had around 25 participants. Other than maybe a free class, this was probably one of the best introductions to programming and Ruby that someone could get for under $100. Maureen put together the entire class, including connecting with the teacher <a href="https://twitter.com/alexch">Alex Chaffee</a> who did an AWESOME job teaching the workshop. If you ever have a chance to buy either of these folks a beer, please do so.</p>

<p><img src="/images/gdi-ruby-workshop.jpg" alt="Girl Develop It Burlington Ruby workshop" /></p>

<h2>Scholarships</h2>

<p>The idea for offering scholarships came from <a href="https://twitter.com/cczona">Carina Zona</a> during one of the Google hangouts. It was something that we wanted to do, but didn&rsquo;t think we&rsquo;d be able to make happen. Later, I found out about a new program through Ruby Central called the <a href="http://rubycentral.org/community#scholarship">Opportunity Scholarship</a> that would match up to $1,500. As the months went by, we were still getting the occasional cat sponsor, and by July had raised over $1K. At this point, we had also sold enough tickets to cover the conference expenses, and were able to set aside tickets to give to scholars. We ended up giving away 11 scholarships, most of which went to women who attended the Girl Develop It workshop, and this was their first tech conference.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p>I must say, <a href="https://twitter.com/btvrubyconf">@btvrubyconf</a> has one of the higher number of women attendees of the confs I&#39;ve been to recently.</p>&mdash; Steve Klabnik (@steveklabnik) <a href="https://twitter.com/steveklabnik/statuses/363691528465559552">August 3, 2013</a></blockquote>


<script async src="http://beerlington.github.io//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>


<p>Side note: If you&rsquo;re organizing a conference, I highly recommend taking advantage of the scholarship funds from Ruby Central. It&rsquo;s a great way to increase diversity, get the word out about your conference, raise a little money, and most importantly, give people an opportunity to attend a conference who would not have been able to otherwise.</p>

<h2>Selling Out</h2>

<p>During the last week before the conference, our headcount was 149 attendees. This included reselling a handful of tickets that we refunded earlier on. I wanted nothing more than to sell this last ticket to say that we had sold out. Sure, we could have just <em>said</em> that we had sold out, but that would have been lame. So finally it was friday night, 15 minutes before the kick off party started, and I got an email saying the last ticket had been sold.</p>

<p>The guy who bought the last ticket became an instant celebrity:</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p>Achievement unlocked. Met the person who bought last <a href="https://twitter.com/btvrubyconf">@btvrubyconf</a> ticket. <a href="http://t.co/Rc20jGH2bO">http://t.co/Rc20jGH2bO</a></p>&mdash; Michael Denomy (@mdenomy) <a href="https://twitter.com/mdenomy/statuses/363999840298356736">August 4, 2013</a></blockquote>


<script async src="http://beerlington.github.io//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>


<p>Since we&rsquo;re planning on keeping next year&rsquo;s attendance at 150 (including speakers), I&rsquo;m hoping the fact that we sold out this year will create demand and make it easier to sell tickets next year.</p>

<h2>Mission Accomplished</h2>

<p>In the end, we reached or exceeded every single one of our goals. We had 150 attendees, nearly doubled the number of speakers, increased female attendance to over 20%, had a considerable increase in sponsors, and were able to hire <a href="http://www.confreaks.com/events/btvruby2013">Confreaks</a> to come and film the talks.</p>

<p>This year:</p>

<ul>
<li>Attendees: 150</li>
<li>Speakers: 12</li>
<li>Women: > 20%</li>
<li>Sponsors/supporters: 12</li>
<li>Confreaks: [✓]</li>
<li>Budget: $24K</li>
</ul>


<p>This post discussed just a few of the things we did for this year&rsquo;s Burlington Ruby Conference that I felt were either unique to our event or contributed to our success. I don&rsquo;t think people will notice too many drastic changes next year as we&rsquo;ll likely focus on polishing things up and continuing to make it an exceptional experience for everyone. If you&rsquo;re interested in hearing more or have specific questions about conferences or cats, <a href="https://twitter.com/beerlington">please reach out</a>!</p>

<p>Thank you so much to everyone who made the event happen, especially <a href="https://twitter.com/brettchalupa">Brett</a>, my supportive <a href="https://twitter.com/vermontgoldens">wife</a>, my mom who provided unlimited phone support, and my partners at <a href="http://agilion.com/">Agilion</a>. I am incredibly grateful to have had the experience and cannot wait to start organizing it again next year. See you at Burlington Ruby in 2014!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Building a strong foundation for Vermont's technology future]]></title>
    <link href="http://beerlington.github.io/blog/2013/04/06/building-a-strong-foundation-for-vermonts-technology-future/"/>
    <updated>2013-04-06T20:34:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://beerlington.github.io/blog/2013/04/06/building-a-strong-foundation-for-vermonts-technology-future</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I went to a <a href="http://www.vermonttechnologyalliance.org/events/event_details.asp?id=308176&amp;group=">VTTA Lunch and Learn</a>
meeting last week focused on &ldquo;Marketing Vermont as a technology state&rdquo;.
I&rsquo;ve had some time to reflect on this objective and wanted to talk about some of the frustrations I&rsquo;ve felt in
trying to address this very issue.</p>

<p>During the lunch session, David Parker of Dealer.com described how Vermont&rsquo;s
greatest opportunity to grow our economy is through the technology sector.
Vermont’s tourism revenue accounts for a small minority of its GDP, yet our
state&rsquo;s marketing is disproportionately focused on tourism.
<a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=o4yr58Xga2A">In his presentation</a>,
Parker expressed that we need to get better at educating
people in science and technology, finding startup capital, and retaining a young
energetic workforce. Instead of proposing concrete actions though, he suggests
&ldquo;changing the rhetoric&rdquo; by talking about what Vermont has to offer. While I
agree with his message, unfortunately talk is cheap and ideas are free, and
neither is worth shit unless you actually stand up and do something.</p>

<p>Unfortunately, getting the word out about these great jobs and companies is not
enough to attract people to our state. One individual at the meeting went as
far as suggesting that every ad in Vermont Life magazine should feature a
cellphone or laptop. Are you kidding me? Vermont is a beautiful place, let&rsquo;s
not change that. Can there not be a balance between technology and Vermont&rsquo;s
simple beauty without the two interfering with the other?</p>

<p>One topic that was missing from the lunch discussion was the role that community
plays in this endeavour. Yes, technology jobs and businesses are undeniably
important, but community is what gives people a sense of belonging. Do artists
and musicians live here because Vermont has one of the <a href="http://www.bls.gov/web/laus/laumstrk.htm">lowest unemployment rates in the country</a>?
No, they live here because there is a community that
supports them. The role of community in the technology sector is no different.</p>

<h2>Community is an Investment, Not an Overnight Success</h2>

<p>Many Americans prefer band-aids to solve problems and don&rsquo;t consider future
repercussions of today&rsquo;s decisions. Why should we invest in renewable energy
when we can solve our immediate energy needs with fossil fuels? Why should we
pay higher taxes when corporations can sponsor our highways? Vermonters are
different. We don&rsquo;t want billboards taking away from Vermont&rsquo;s beauty. We would
rather pay $15 for a hamburger made from locally raised cows than $4 for a
Big Mac. More importantly though, our small communities thrive because they&rsquo;re not
looking for short term payoff. Community, like renewable energy, is a long
term investment and not a band-aid.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m organizing a software developer conference this summer called the
<a href="http://burlingtonruby.com/">Burlington Ruby Conference</a>.
Last year was our first time hosting the event and it attracted
80 developers for a weekend of networking and education in Burlington. Only about
25% of the attendees were from Vermont. The rest were from Boston, Montreal,
New York, and other parts of New England. We even had two guys from Denmark and
one from Mississippi. We also had a small number of women attend, but this year we have
been putting a lot of energy into increasing that number. We reached out to the
female developer and speaker communities, published a <a href="http://burlingtonruby.com/diversity.html">diversity statement</a> and
<a href="http://burlingtonruby.com/conduct.html">code of conduct</a>, and have teamed up with
<a href="http://www.girldevelopit.com/chapters/burlington">Girl Develop It</a> to offer low cost
training in conjunction with the conference. What other technology event in
Vermont can make similar claims?</p>

<p>This year we&rsquo;ve reached out to numerous Vermont companies soliciting sponsorship
for the conference and have been met with the same response each time. &ldquo;Sorry,
not interested. We don&rsquo;t do Ruby, we do _____&rdquo;. Fill in the blank with
Java, .Net, LOLCODE, whatever. That&rsquo;s great, but these companies are obviously
missing the point. When was the last time there was a Java or .Net conference of this caliber in Vermont?
This is an opportunity to support the very community that these
companies are trying to hire from. Just because a developer writes Java code
to pay the bills, doesn&rsquo;t necessarily mean he or she wants to do this in their
free time. If you look at the
<a href="http://burlingtonruby.org/buruco2012/">speakers we had last year</a>, it clearly wasn&rsquo;t all
about Ruby. We had talks on building location based apps, database scaling,
and multiple JavaScript talks from some of the most respected people in these fields.</p>

<p>Why have a Ruby conference then you ask? Simple. The Ruby community as a whole
represents the type of community that we know will thrive in Vermont. The people
are passionate, helpful, and strong advocates for diversity. Ruby developers
also tend to be at the forefront of best practices. Combined, these characteristics
lead to a vibrant, successful community. Just look at the number of other
<a href="http://lanyrd.com/topics/ruby/">regional Ruby conferences</a> that have sprung
up in the last few years. Ruby may not be the
<a href="http://www.codinghorror.com/blog/2013/03/why-ruby.html">cool language anymore</a>,
but the community is thriving. In my years of being a
Ruby developer, I&rsquo;ve never met someone who said they only use Ruby because it
pays the bills.</p>

<p>This conference is going to happen whether we have local support or not. We are
fortunate to live in a city where our costs to organize the event will be covered
by ticket sales alone. We&rsquo;ve also added a crowd-sourced fundraising effort
called &ldquo;<a href="http://burlingtonruby.com/cat.html">Burlington Ruby Cats</a>&rdquo;
that is not only raising money for the conference,
but also for the Humane Society of Chittenden County. Having sponsors would allow
us to do things above and beyond what a typical conference can offer such as
scholarships for students and underrepresented groups like women and minorities.
Equally as important though, having support from local sponsors shows that these
companies actually care about our community. We are not organizing this
conference to make money, infact we will be lucky if we break even given
everything we want to do. We are hosting a lakeside BBQ and providing professional
recordings of the talks free of charge. We are organizing the conference because
we want to invest in our community. We want people to think about this conference
when they think of Burlington, Vermont; thereby helping to achieve our goal of
&ldquo;Marketing Vermont as a technology state&rdquo;.</p>

<h2>How can I get involved?</h2>

<p>Don&rsquo;t get me wrong, the Vermont software community as it stands today is awesome.
I participated in (<a href="http://beerlington.github.io/blog/2012/10/21/how-we-won-hackvt/">and won</a>)
the 2nd annual Vermont Hackathon last October. This
event was targeted toward Vermont developers and the amount of support that local
businesses gave was incredible. This was a great success for our community,
but we can&rsquo;t limit ourselves to a handful of these events a year, or only focus
on the business side of Vermont&rsquo;s technology economy.</p>

<p>I also help organize a number of different software related user groups in the
Burlington area. Our first group, the <a href="http://www.btvwag.org/">Burlington Web Application Group</a>
(BTVWAG) typically has 30-50 people at any given meetup, and our latest group,
<a href="http://burlingtonjs.org/">Burlington JS</a>, filled all 35 of its slots in the first day it was announced.
These groups are run by volunteers and represent exactly what our technology
community is about.</p>

<p>People ask me after every meetup how they can get involved, but then I never hear
back from them. Step up folks! Acknowledging that we have a problem is the first
step, but taking action is the only way that things will change. There are a
number of community members who get this and have devoted countless hours of their free
time to building the community. Aside from the hackathon,
<a href="http://vtcodecamp.org/">Vermont Code Camp</a>, <a href="http://www.techjamvt.com/">Vermont Tech Jam</a>,
and <a href="http://btvgig.org/">BTVGig</a> are other examples of events and initiatives led by
passionate Vermonters who want to see our community grow. We also have folks
like Jen Mincar at <a href="http://www.officesquaredvt.com/">Office Squared</a> who provide
places for these groups to gather, free of charge.</p>

<p>Vermont has jobs and an incredible opportunity for growth through technology,
so now is the time to start investing in our community, and investing in our
future. Please <a href="https://twitter.com/beerlington">reach out</a> if you want to
join us in building a strong foundation for Vermont&rsquo;s technology future.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
